PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a Senior Digital Designer and a user experience enthurisast. I enjoy working across multiple platforms to create solutions that are both captivating and easy to use. My goal is to find the best user-centered solution within a given constraint.

I have been working in the online industry for almost 8 years. Currently specialising in user centered design methodologies, I'm looking for a position where I can put in practice my recent and collective knowledge.

CURRENTLY

Working at The New Zealand Herald. APN News Media, Auckland.

Finished a UX course at Billy Blue College. Ultimo, Sydney.

MOST ACTIVE TECH SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite. Photoshop. Illustrator. Indesign. Flash.

User flow & Prototyping. Axure. UXpin.

Development. HTML5. CSS3. Sass/Susy. Jquery. Git. Sublime.

ABILITIES

User Experience Methodologies.

Discovery of the best solutions through personas, user journeys, wireframes, prototypes, testing and iteration.

Visual and Interface Design.

Conversion of solutions into engaging and compelling visual designs.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Digital Designer

The New Zealand Herald

FEB 2011 - PRESENT

Currently creating unique user experiences for a number of projects, custom design and development for special coverage; for desktop and mobile.

Designing and developing solutions to display complex information. Researching user needs and designing interactions to introduce new products. Working across teams to find the best design solution.

- Front end development.
- Applying user experience methodologies.
- Working with editorial on special coverages.

SOFTWARE:

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE - HTML5 CSS3 - SASS - GIT - MAPBOX - CARTODB - TABLEAU - AXURE

Web Designer

Moko Digital

NOV 2009 - OCT 2010

Created concepts and visual design for websites and branding.

Some small custom development as well. Logo design and branding. Most of the time working as a team to find solutions to evolve our client's brand online.

- Visual design.
- Development.

SOFTWARE:

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE - HTML5 CSS3 - JQUERY - FLASH - VISUAL STUDIO

Designer for Web and Print

Trio Group

APR 2007 - NOV 2009

Designed and developed sites for internal use and digital editions.

Worked for renowned brands like Air New Zealand and Coca-Cola Amatil. Designed and Mac Operator work like prepress and checkups for print.

• Print and Digital Editions

SOFTWARE:

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE - HTML5 CSS3 - FLASH - ADOBE ACROBAT

Designer for Web and Print

APN News and Media | Wises Maps | Finda

MAR 2006 - APR 2007

Design of advertising for print and web. Customisation of maps.

Used their CMS and sometimes custom HTML to put online adverts on Wises Maps, Sella and Finda. Flash banners and helped to create a workflow to convert print to online using XML in InDesign.

Design for print and some custom HTML.

SOFTWARE:

ILLUSTRATOR - PHOTOSHOP - INDESIGN - ADOBE ACROBAT - HTML - FLASH

Graphic Designer

Ponto Forte Comunicações

MAR 2001 - FEB 2003

Designed for print and followed guidelines from brands and art directors.

Worked hand in hand and learned from other creative designers and art directors. Experienced the design world first hand and developed my skills as a designer working on top Brazilian brands.

- Designed following briefs and brand guidelines.
- Print and Mac Operator tasks.

SOFTWARE:

ILLUSTRATOR - PHOTOSHOP - QUARKXPRESS - ADOBE ACROBAT

EDUCATION AND COURSES

UX Design & Research

Billy Blue College of Design - SYDNEY

MAY 2015

Practical and theoretical skills to research, design and test websites.

Industry best-practices and tools for researching, designing and testing websites. Hands on practical projects. Planning, interaction design and usability testing.

- **Research and identify user groups** and archetypes that for a digital product.
- Design research in the form of Persona matrices and customer journey maps.
- Wireframes and interactive prototypes design and functionality (Axure).
- Plan and conduct usability testing and writing reports.

LECTURER:

MIKE FEGHALI: HAS DESIGNED AND ARCHITECTED SOME OF AUSTRALIA'S BEST-KNOWN EXPERIENCES WITH CLIENTS INCLUDING TASTE.COM.AU, MYSCHOOL, CBA, WESTPAC, YAHOO!7 AND NRMA. HE SPECIALISES IN IMPROVING HUMAN PERFORMANCE AND CUSTOMER ENGAGEMENT THROUGH THE USE OF INTUITIVE DIGITAL INTERFACES. HE LECTURES THE NEXT GENERATION OF EXPERIENCE DESIGNERS.

UX Crash Course

Design Assembly - AUCKLAND

APRIL 2015

Hands-on experience of a digital UX design project from start to finish.

In this intense workshop they gave us practical experience about some of the most common activities in a typical user-centered digital design process.

- Experience user research.
- Ideation and interaction design.
- Rapid prototyping.
- User testing.

LECTURER:

MATT GOULD: TRAINED AS A GRAPHIC DESIGNER ORIGINALLY, BUT LIKE MOST UX PRACTITIONERS BRINGS TO HIS WORK A WIDE RANGE OF SKILLS AND EXPERIENCES. HE IS A DESIGN COACH FOR NEW ZEALAND TRADE AND ENTERPRISE'S 'BETTER BY DESIGN' DESIGN INTEGRATION PROGRAMME AND ONE OF THE TEACHERS IN AUT'S INTERACTION DESIGN MINOR.

Diploma of Digital Media (with distinction)

MDS (Media Design School) - AUCKLAND

APR 2008 - FEB 2010

Taught us how to communicate using text, images and form to create and develop meaningful interactions. Graphic, motion and interactive design. PHP, ActionScript, Video Editing, Flash and Animation graphics.

- Web design best practices.
- Design and development.
- Video, sound editing and animation.

Formed part of the industry panel in 2012

Technologies for Multimedia

SCHOOL OF VISUAL ARTS - BUENOS AIRES

DEC 1999

Provided us with the knowledge and skills relating to graphics, audio, video, animation and web. This programme aimed to provide a broad range approach to digital media.

- Digital illustration, animation and storyboarding.
- Digital imaging: Photoshop.
- Video editing.

Graphic Designer

UBA - BUENOS AIRES

DEC 1999 - OCT 2000

Conceptualisation and production of visual materials that effectively communicate information and ideas for a wide range of media.

- Design foundations: Typography, grids, color theory.
- Composition and images.
- Editorial and layout.

Graphic Designer

Fernando Fader Polytechnic - BUENOS AIRES

MAR 1990 - DEC 1996

Techniques and methodologies for design and promotion. This is a general foundation course running for three years and another three years of specialisation.

•••••

AWARDS

Best Innovation in Multimedia

Canon Media Awards - AUCKLAND

APR 2012

In recognition for all round excellence of work.

EXPERT

SKILLS SUMMARY

PHOTOSHOP:

ILLUSTRATOR:	EXPERT	
ILLUSTRATOR.	EXIEKI	
INDESIGN:	ADVANCED	•••••
AXURE:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
FLASH:	ADVANCED	•••••
DREAMWEAVER:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
SUBLIME:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
CSS ₃ HTML ₅ :	ADVANCED	•••••
GIT:	BASIC	••00000
SASS SUSY:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
JAVASCRIPT:	BASIC	••00000
JQUERY:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
ACTIONSCRIPT:	ADVANCED	•••••
TABLEAU:	INTERMEDIATE	••••000
MAPPING:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
DATA VIZ:	INTERMEDIATE	••••